Guide to the Yale College Committees Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale College committees records
1894-1977
RU 732
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
The records consist of correspondence, meeting minutes, memoranda, and reports documenting the operations and activities of various Yale College committees. Included are reports on scholarship committees, statistics on course offerings, minutes of the Course of Study and Honors Committees, petitions for degrees, minutes of the Committee on the Status of Minority Students, and minutes and correspondence from Yale College committees concerning undergraduate policies and activities.
Yale College (1887- )
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-D (YRG 9-D), Records of Yale College committees.
Conditions Governing Access
While this collection as a whole is available for research, parts of it may be restricted due to law, university policy or fragility. Any restricted material will be noted as such.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by committee name.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, meeting minutes, memoranda, and reports documenting the operations and activities of various Yale College committees. Included are reports on scholarship committees, statistics on course offerings, minutes of the Course of Study and Honors Committees, petitions for degrees, minutes of the Committee on the Status of Minority Students, and minutes and correspondence from Yale College committees concerning undergraduate policies and activities.
Yale College (1887- )
- Yale College committees records, Series I
  - Committee on Admissions. List of members from, 1901-1920 undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Courses. Minutes, circa 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Committee on Elective Courses. Report Statistics of the Elective Courses since 1884 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Committee on the Enforcement of College Rules. Minutes, 1916-1920 (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
  - Joint subcommittee of the Executive Committee and the Course of Study Committee on Acceleration, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Committee on the Future of the College and Graduate School. Report, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Committee on the Revision of Rules. Report, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Numbers and Scholarship. Report, 1903 April (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
  - Committee on the Status of Minority Students in Yale College. Minutes, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 11-14)
  - Committee on Undergraduate Activities. Minutes, 1941-1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Committee on Week-end Absences. Report, 1908 March 5 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Pre-Registration Orientation Program (PROP). Reports, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 17)